[ Watch on KissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 17]
So this is the wish-granting tree
you told me about?
Wait here.
Sir, one wishing plaque, please.
Thank you.
Make a wish.
Your Lordship,
what did you wish for?
Whether my wish comes true or not
doesn't depend on the will of Heaven,
but solely on myself.
So this wish of mine
is for you.
I wish you
auspiciousness every day
and that all your wishes come true.
Shen Run,
I saw you in him
once again.
Now, I can no longer tell the difference between you two.
Is he the person I'm missing?
Perhaps you two really are the same person.
It's said that
Lord Yan Rui from the capital
has swift and decisive methods
and a heart of steel.
He kills corrupt officials,
suppresses famine,
and exterminates northern bandits.
The whole nation is shocked,
and the people praise him.
Great!
But everyone,
do you really think
he is a court official?
An informant
has brought news.
That Lord Yan
isn't even surnamed Yan!
He's a
fake!
A fake?
He's a fake.
My Lady.
Lord Yan asked me to tell you
that Cui is fine now
and will be released from prison soon.
Okay, got it.
Did you hear?
That Lord Yan, who provided disaster relief,
is a fake.
What?
Impersonating a court official
is a capital offense!
Keep your voice down.
People are watching.
The real Lord Yan is already dead.
This person right now
is just a mere commoner
who borrowed the identity,
took the title,
and transformed himself
into a great official!
Is that so?
You ask who he is?
It's scary to say.
This person walks the dark path
and talks about rules.
His sword never leaves his side.
When unsheathed, it must see blood.
Legend has it
that in one night,
he beheaded 17 people.
No one has seen him
strike a second time.
Now you know
why he comes from a civil official background,
but can brave the northern bandits.
What?
So he's a bandit.
No wonder he acts so unconventionally.
So what if he is fake?
We still like him even if he is fake.
He works for us common people.
Yes.
What? Are we not allowed to speak our minds?
Between true and false,
it's hard to tell loyalty from treason.
Listen to me tell you
the details.
In just one night,
the rumors about Lord Yan's identity
have spread all over Hengtang.
Qingyuan, if you are worried,
why don't you go see him?
I heard
Concubine Mei is not doing well
and might be sent out of the residence.
She deserves it.
Fourth Lady.
The case is settled.
You can leave now.
Yes.
Have you thought about where to go?
Can someone like me
still choose my own future?
Yes, you can.
I can arrange a new identity for you
and give you some money to settle down.
You can go anywhere,
choose to get married,
or start a small business.
You can live
any kind of life you want.
No one will know you.
What do you need me to do?
You don't need to do anything for me.
Do you
not hate me?
You were just a pawn.
Even without you,
there would be someone else.
Cui'er,
live your life well.
When you have the ability,
help those around you
so they can also have the right to choose.
That would be the best way to repay me.
Thank you.
Baoxian.
She fell asleep.
Isn't Lord Yan with you?
I'm here precisely because of him.
Do you know
he bears heavy responsibilities?
[Danyue Pavilion]
Now, because of you,
he is distracted
and delaying important matters.
If you know him,
you should know that
once he makes up his mind,
no one can sway him.
It's impossible for me to change him.
This path
guarantees certain death.
Any slight distraction
will make him fail completely.
So having you by his side
is a disaster waiting to happen.
[Danyue Pavilion]
Che.
Step aside!
If you still remember your family name,
let me get rid of this disaster!
For what we need to do,
what good does it do?
If it reminds you
of our family's deep grievances,
her death won't be in vain!
[Danyue Pavilion]
Che.
I have never forgotten.
For so many years,
I lived like a walking corpse.
Only when I am by her side
do I feel alive.
[Danyue Pavilion]
You only have one life.
You have a mission to fulfill.
The sword in your hand cannot rust because of feelings.
Think it through.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Who is he?
And what are the deep grievances he just mentioned?
Living in this world,
it's inevitable to have some feuds.
He and I walked out of the same hell.
We bear the same blood debts.
It's just that
he suffers more than I do.
Yan Rui thinks I'm acting out of hatred,
hating him for falling in love.
No.
He is wrong.
What I fear is not Xie Qingyuan herself,
but the people possibly pulling strings behind her.
The Xie family knows too well how to kill.
What if they don't use blades,
but tenderness?
You can't gamble your life on a moment of weakness.
Xie Qingyuan might be innocent,
but what I must do
[Frugality Cultivates Virtue]
cannot risk any "what-ifs"
and "perhaps."
I'm not killing your beloved.
I'm just eliminating every
possibility that could destroy you.
Che.
What are you doing here?
Do you know how agonizing it was
to lie under Mother's dead body,
and feel her body
turn cold
bit by bit?
Do you know that
I crawled out of a pile of dead bodies?
I faced that dead silence for so long.
Those people
were all our family.
You don't know.
That's why,
for your own selfish feelings,
you forgot
the responsibility on our shoulders.
Che.
I really thought you were dead back then.
Until I saw you again later,
I didn't know you had suffered so much.
Yes.
I've fallen for Qingyuan.
If hatred is involuntary,
what about love?
Can I control love?
But I know
I can control my own life.
My life is tied to yours.
Before our father's name is cleared,
and before our enemies pay in blood,
I will never waver.
I just hope...
I just hope that after we resolve everything,
we can let go of the past
and live a good life.
Somebody...
Somebody!
Second Madam,
it is time for you to leave.
Where am I going?
On the orders of the Head Madam,
I am to take you to the estate
to pray for the Old Madam.
I am not going.
Since marrying into this residence,
I never planned to leave this house.
I'm not going anywhere.
I almost forgot.
Eldest Young Master
has sent a letter.
Give my son's letter
to me.
[Respectfully to Madam Mei of the Xie family in Hengtang, from Xie Zhenglun]
After committing such a grave mistake,
you don't deserve to read the letter from a Xie family descendant.
You lowly maidservant!
From now on,
-the Eldest and Second Young Master -Give me the letter.
will be registered under the Head Madam's name.
Take her away.
Yes.
You lowly maidservant!
Give me the letter!
Stop!
What are you doing?
Second Young Master.
Mother.
Mother!
Get lost!
Zhengjun.
Mother.
Help me.
Your brother sent a letter.
When he left,
I couldn't even see him off.
I want to see what he said to me in the letter.
-Mother. -Help me.
Okay.
Mother, don't worry.
Take it easy. I will find a way.
I will think of something.
[Wuzhu Courtyard]
Madam,
the one in Liuhua Courtyard
is probably so angry
that she is about to draw her last breath.
If she really doesn't survive,
she only has herself to blame.
She was competitive her whole life.
Even now,
she's still so stubborn.
Madam,
Young Master Zhengjun
is still waiting outside.
[Wuzhu Courtyard]
Second Young Master.
The Head Madam
has been feeling unwell recently.
She just lay down and hasn't gotten up yet.
Why don't you
come back to visit another day?
I'll just wait here.
Madam.
Young Master Zhengjun said
he'd just wait there.
Forget it.
Let him in.
Head Madam.
I just heard my brother sent a letter.
Could you give me the letter
-so my mother... -I know why you are here.
But do you know
why I made you kneel in the rain for so long?
Your brother
went to the battlefield.
You're now the only man in the Xie family.
We have
high hopes for you,
and we hope you can be sensible
and shoulder the responsibilities of the Xie family.
Your Mother
is a sinner of the Xie family.
According to the rules,
she has no right to read this letter.
So,
I ought to withhold it.
You are absolutely right, Head Madam.
But the bond between my mother and me runs deep.
I really cannot bear to see her
in such a difficult situation.
Zhengjun, you've grown up.
You know how to care for people now.
Good.
I know you're a filial and good child.
But you must understand that
she
is currently bearing guilt.
If you blindly get close to her,
I'm afraid
it will displease your father
and affect your bright future.
You and Zhenglun
are now registered under my name.
You're like my own biological sons.
I hope you
understand my intentions.
Perhaps
your older brother's words
will carry some weight with your father.
I understand.
Thank you, Head Madam.
Mother has been locked up.
I heard that soon,
she will be sent to that remote estate.
What should we do now?
[Mother has been locked up. I heard that soon,]
[she will be sent to that remote estate.]
[What should we do now?]
Grandmother asked me to call you for dinner.
No matter the problem,
you must first take care of your health
before thinking of a way.
Fourth Sister.
Do you hate my mother and me?
Those things
were all done by Second Madam herself.
The sins of the parents don't fall upon their children.
I can still distinguish right from wrong
and won't take my anger out on others.
I'm sorry.
Are you writing a letter to Big Brother?
They're taking my mother to the estate.
Usually, Brother makes the decisions
on all the major matters.
I want to consult him.
But he is already working very hard at the front line,
so you don't want to bother him with family matters?
I'll help you.
Everything is fine at home.
[To my dear brother]
Do not worry.
The weather has been getting colder recently.
I hope you take care of yourself, brother.
Put on more clothes
and stay warm.
Mother and I
miss you very much.
We pray day and night
for your good health.
Everything at home
is the same.
Mother is in good health.
I am studying diligently
without slacking off.
I hope you
can find time
to write us a letter
to ease our longing.
We also pray for
your early triumph
and safe return home.
[I hope you can find time to write us a letter]
[to ease our longing.]
[Everything is fine at home. Do not worry. The weather has been getting colder recently.]
[I hope you take care of yourself, brother. Put on more clothes and stay warm.]
Second Brother.
Please make sure to send a trusted person
to deliver this to Big Brother.
Don't let anyone else handle this.
Fourth Sister.
Thank you.
[Everything is fine at home. Do not worry.]
Zhengjun has really grown up.
He knows to report only the good news now.
That won't do.
[Your brother, Zhengjun]
Send this to Zhenglun immediately.
It must not be delayed.
Yes, Madam.
The rainy season in Hengtang has arrived.
I wonder how many flowers and plants
won't survive this time.
Make way!
[Dongmen General Store]
-This way, General. -Report!
Please.
To the family of General Xie Zhenglun,
Vanguard General
of the Ningwu Army.
Since the flames of war ignited at the border,
your son Zhenglun,
loyal and courageous,
rose up
and requested to fight.
He left his home to face the crisis.
He was besieged in an isolated city.
The city fell,
and to protect the people,
he was pierced by countless arrows.
His sacrifice cannot be repaid.
In his final moments,
his mind was still clear.
He remembered your deep grace in raising him,
and regretted that he could not return to care for you.
His words were choked with sobs,
and everyone who heard him was moved.
His loyal and courageous act
and his awe-inspiring heroism
are enough to be a model for the whole army,
and admired by future generations.
I sincerely hope you
and your family will restrain your grief
and take care of yourselves.
His heroic deeds
will surely go down in history
and be remembered forever.
April 20th, 8th year of Jingxi.
Delivered by urgent horse relay.
Zhenglun!
My grandson!
How could you bear to let an elderly like me
bury a young man like you?
Mother! Mother!
Mother, please restrain your grief.
My son!
Second Brother.
About the letter you sent that day,
are you sure
it didn't pass through anyone else's hands?
I don't know what to do.
I can't care about anything else now.
My brother is gone.
What should I do?
What will happen to Mother now?
He was fine the last time he wrote.
My condolences.
But this matter is of great importance.
Second Brother, please think it over.
Here you are.
Qingyuan.
Come with me.
Recently,
much has happened in the household,
with Zhenglun's passing being a huge blow.
After mulling it over,
in this family,
I only feel assured
entrusting this matter to you.
Whatever you order,
as far as I'm capable,
I will definitely do my best.
[Respectfully to Madam Mei of the Xie family in Hengtang]
This is the letter Zhenglun
wrote to Concubine Mei.
Concubine Mei is a sinner,
and I was afraid she'd cause more trouble,
so I held onto it.
Concubine Mei
killed your biological mother.
She also paid the price she deserved.
But no matter what,
she is Zhenglun's biological mother.
Respect for the dead comes first.
This letter can be considered Zhenglun's last words.
Take this letter
along with the obituary
and give them to Concubine Mei.
If you can,
comfort her with a few words.
Yes.
If you don't finish washing
these clothes today,
you're not allowed to eat tonight.
You'll be locked in the woodshed!
She's not asking me to deliver
a letter today.
It's clearly the last straw
that will break Mei Yinghua.
Nanny Qin.
Fourth Lady,
why are you here?
I have to talk to Second Madam.
Mother, on the day of my departure,
I was unable to bid you farewell in person.
I feel quite regretful.
I wonder if Zhengjun
is taking good care of you at home.
I miss you very much.
After all, you are the mother
who has cherished me since I was little.
Mother.
When I'm done with my work here,
I'll go home and accompany you.
Whether you want to chant sutras
or go to the estate,
I'll be there with you, alright?
As long as my son, Zhenglun,
is doing well,
I am assured.
Qingyuan.
Thank you.
Is there anything else?
♪ Waiting for a dream to sink into the depths of the night ♪
♪ Waiting for a rain to wash away the heat burning in my eyes ♪
[Eighth year of Jingxi, Emergency Delivery from the Privy Council]
♪ Waiting for a few flowers to bloom, then quietly fall ♪
My son, Zhenglun!
♪ Only then do I understand right from what's wrong and bitter ♪
♪ Pear blossoms drift through the courtyard, fluttering like snowflakes in a song ♪
♪ Singing the silence of love and hate ♪
♪ Which moment is hypothetical, and which is a real choice? ♪
♪ Who is drifting aimlessly in the wind? ♪
Zhenglun...
♪ I wonder why joy is always so scarce in this world ♪
I wasn't the only one who harmed Fifth Madam.
♪ I wonder, is that tear a loss or a gain? ♪
You shouldn't have taken the blame!
♪ Two souls trapped on the opposite banks of life and death ♪
♪ May you and I overcome karma's bonds ♪
Zhenglun...
Mother!
♪ Waiting for a dream to sink into the depths of the night ♪
Zhenglun?
Zhenglun...
♪ Waiting for a rain to wash away the heat burning in my eyes ♪
Hurry.
Come home to me.
♪ Waiting for a few flowers to bloom, then quietly fall ♪
Come here.
♪ Only then do I understand right from what's wrong and bitter ♪
Hurry.
♪ Pear blossoms drift through the courtyard, fluttering like snowflakes in a song ♪
And you.
I told you
♪ Singing the silence of love and hate ♪
to pick this flower.
Go over there.
Take that flowerpot away.
♪ Which moment is hypothetical, and which is a real choice? ♪
Toss it.
Clean this up.
Third Madam is kind-hearted.
♪ Who is drifting aimlessly in the wind? ♪
After how Concubine Mei treated her,
she still took the trouble to send people
to deliver all her belongings to the estate.
Concubine Mei used to be the most arrogant and domineering.
♪ I wonder why joy is always so scarce in this world ♪
She always had to be the best at everything.
Who would have thought she'd end up a lunatic?
♪ I wonder, is that tear a loss or a gain? ♪
Sometimes, going mad
is also a relief.
♪ Two souls trapped on the opposite banks of life and death ♪
Hurry up.
I haven't seen Third Madam for a long time.
I'm going to Hanxiang Parlor.
You go back first.
♪ May you and I overcome karma's bonds ♪
Yes.
♪ No more wandering and worrying ♪
The young master is in mourning for his mother,
and with your eldest brother's passing,
your eldest sister is in an even worse mood.
Fortunately, with your support,
the herbal shop
is able to operate normally.
Eldest Sister and the Young Lord
are deeply in love.
They can't marry because of the mourning period,
which is truly a pity.
We rise
and fall together.
Born into this noble household,
we are destined
to share its honor and disgrace.
Who could ever remain untainted?
So did you purge the ranks...
also to keep the peace in the Xie family?
What are you talking about?
I don't understand.
You knew
Concubine Mei loved flowers,
so you poisoned the soil
and drove her insane.
Right?
Second Madam killed Chunqing.
I was just avenging her.
Third Madam.
If you wanted to avenge my mother,
you could have used this poison 9 years ago.
But why did you have to wait till today?
Isn't it because the mastermind
only gave you permission today?
That day, you publicly
testified for me
not because Qinghe persuaded you, right?
It was because the mastermind
instructed you to.
Right?
This person
is First Madam, right?
Who would have thought
that the much-wronged Head Madam
would be the mastermind behind all this?
It's my fault.
I'm the one
who harmed Chunqing
and Fifth Madam.
She threatened me with that
and made me do her bidding.
It was me.
Because I could no longer bear Second Madam's disdain
and oppression,
I told First Madam
the secret that euphorbia and Congxian Grass
are lethal when taken together.
But I really didn't expect that
the one who got harmed in the end
would be Chunqing.
I lived in seclusion because
I didn't want to get involved in their fights anymore.
I didn't want to be involved in their crimes anymore.
But this time...
Although I was instigated by her,
I really wanted to avenge Chunqing,
so I fulfilled her wish!
Third Madam.
I don't hate you.
What I hate is,
why is it that every time
the ones who bear the consequences of these struggles
are always innocent people
like my mother and my eldest brother?
Child.
You don't understand.
If the wind in this world never stops blowing,
the trees in this world
will never stop swaying.
One Concubine Mei has gone mad,
but there will be another.
Qingyuan!